# Akhil Sharatchandra Upadhyaya



#### Personal Data:

Phone: +91 98866 45025

Email Id :

akhil.sharatchandra.upadhyaya@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/akhil-upadhyaya-90391013/

DOB: 23<sup>rd</sup> January 1988

Address: G2, #15, 7<sup>th</sup> Main, 1<sup>st</sup> Cross, Sarvabhowma Nagar, Chikkalsandra, Bangalore

## Skills:

Collaboration Analysis and Presentation Team Management Event Management Agile Methodologies Story Telling

## **Tools and Utilities:**

SAS Certified Base Programmer SAS Certified Business Intelligence Developer Microsoft Presentation Microsoft Excel

Python Mainframes Environment

Business Systems: Worked on multiple systems to understand the structure and be able to stitch to form a *dashboard* for senior management, data metrics included data from workflow, new application processing and performance management systems.

Workflow System :

Application Origination System

AAPS3/AAPS4 FEPS/OBS-RCS

Omniflow

HUB

Decision System

SMG3 TRIAD

Whirl

Quality Management Tool :

Input Quality Transaction Quality

## **Education:**

Electrical and Electronics Engineering svesvaraya Technological Unive

Currenly persuing Financial Risk Management from Edupristine

## Language:

English

## Hobbies:

Travelling Playing Table Tennis

## Achievements:

Part of team which won prestigious Dragon's Den award from Global Office of COO, HSBC, Twice

Recognised in Capital One as a young talent

Recognised in RNSIT for my contribution for

Recognised in RNSIT for my contribution in Cultural Activities

Objective:

Provide Analytical Solutions through effective use of mining of large banking data, deep dive data analysis on portfolio metrics. Track and maintain key performance metrics and portfolio quality. Liaison with technology and business teams to the ongoing development of key change delivery to support the data infrastructure to ensure all policies, processes, development are working efficiently so that all required change are built and implemented suitably with the help of a team of analysts.

Skilled in BFSI industry with close to 9 Years experience in Analytics, Operations, Reporting, Data Infrastructure and Risk Management Related field. Currently pursuing Financial Risk Management Program with the objective of completing the Charter along with Global Association of Risk Professionals (GARP) Certification.

## Work Experience:

Manager, HSBC Electronic Data Processing Pvt Ltd (September 2014- March 2019):

- Analysis of the workflow data framework for understanding the overall estimation of the turnaround time classification of volumes and queue. Helped reduce the TAT by close to 40% by development of *One Stop Methodology*.
- Analysis of Decision System referred applications to understand the nature of referral and the resulting workload created. The idea being to reduce the volume of work and suggestion of system automation.
- To identify applications journey in the process and try to understand where blockages can be removed.
- Portfolio Management Activities including Monthly Report Packs which includes KPI, KRI metrics, Credit Limit Increase/Decrease, Direct Marketing and Balance Transfer campaign report back in Canada Region as completely new setup. Priority was to establish Business Confidence to set up BAU activities in GAC.
- Risk Book, RTB Packs, Moc Presentations, Adhoc Analysis for Region Specific Strategy Meetings.
- Hands on experience in change delivery Data maturity Development of database- Support agile methodology (to help Dev Ops in Storytelling) – Strategic solution for long term automation for 20 product country combination for the QV tool developed internally.
- Data Validation, Data Analysis for Senior Management. Documentation with the help of a team for Application system, Workflow system, Decision system- 20 country product combination being deployed. Interaction with multiple stakeholders involved for project
- Business travel to understand Canada Mortgage and Credit Cards Business.

## Principal Coordinator, Capital One Financial Services (June 2012 - August 2014):

- Worked on Operations analytics and reporting using Mainframe SAS, SQL and VBA.
- Maintained the Dialler process which makes automated calls to customer (Access/Sql/Unix).
- Automated E-P Tool for Servicing Operational Performance Review reports produced by HR team. Report picks data from multiple data source, create reports and updates PowerPoint. Saved 20 FTE hours/Month by automating the report. (Excel/PPT/VBA)
- As part of the Credit Lending team, responsible for monthly reports on the Credit Lending Industry which includes views on Capital One's Portfolio Volume, Portfolio Quality, Portfolio performance, Modification (Default Remediation) Performance, and other
- Created DNS Tool as a process improvement measure for reporting. The tool automated the process of extraction, stamping and sharing of the reports to the stakeholders. Saved nearly 25% daily Bandwidth of an Analyst.
- Handled the daily dashboard for Inbound Call Statistics. The dashboard delivers daily operational metrics to the operation managers who use the numbers to do resource planning for the day. Also involved in analysis in case of variance of call received and the call volumes forecasted.
- Created a tool for tracking the issues/risk events for compliance analytics team.
- Adhoc analysis for Operations Manager in Partnerships Space for campaign management, Quality analysis for paper applications
- Involved in automation of reports, placing QC and improving efficiency across Teams.

## Senior Process Associate, WNS Global Services (January 2010 - March 2012)

- Maintained the scheduled and batch reports on the SAS BI platform. Tasks included analyzing business functions, preparing detailed technical specifications for both ETL jobs and reporting.
- Troubleshooting, fix erroneous data and run ETL jobs to load the data mart using SAS Info Maps
- Responsible for the loading of external data into the database management system using SAS and/or SQL code as necessary. To be able to receive, track and load the external data into the database system and answer client questions concerning the processing of this data. To interact with suppliers of external data in negotiating format and method of transfer from said supplier to Company.
- Performing Analysis of the consultant's performance, sales and analyzing the variance between the actual and the forecasted data. Using Advanced EXCEL for reporting.
- The project lead to automation of the process of valuation, thereby reducing the error and saving upto 30 FTE hours of an Associate/Month
- Delivered the performance of the unit which was also used to do performance analysis of the FTE, which was linked to the incentive

Consistently been a top rate achiever, with motivation to constantly learn and understand business problems and deliver under stressful situation with a reliance on collaboration, integrity and team work.

Additional Responsibilities: Part of a team which helped organised activities to reduce stress and build strong team bonding. Interested in attending Corporate Social Responsibility Program and Sustainability Sessions.

## Declaration:

I, Akhil Sharatchandra Upadhyaya, affirm that all the information mentioned in the resume is correct to the best of my knowledge. Recommendation Letter from my superiors can be provided on need basis.